# Yeswanth sai Vuddula

Chicago, IL |Phone: +1(773)-977-5097 | Yvuddula@hawk.iit.edu | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

### **Summary:**

An aspiring data analyst/engineer with over 1 year of work experience on multiple technologies with expertise on Python, R, SQL, statistical analysis, predictive modeling, data visualization, and databases (MySQL, Microsoft & Oracle SQL Server), with excellent problem-solving, communicating, analyzing and programming skills.

#### **Education:**

Illinois Institute of Technology (Aug 2022- May2024)

Masters in Computer Science

SRM Institute of Science & Technology (2017-2021)

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering

**Technical Skills:** 

**Programming Languages**: Python, Java, HTML / CSS, SQL, C, C++, R, Hadoop, React.

Cloud: AWS (EC2, S3, IAM, RDS, REDSHIFT, EMR, VPC and Cloud Watch) and Azure(databricks)

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server

**Tools**: VS Code, Eclipse, Android Studio, Spyder, Jupyter Notebook, Oracle SQL Developer, Microsoft Excel **Others**: PowerBI, PySpark, Git, Tableau, MS Project, MATLAB, Linux, Numpy, pandas, Sklearn, Matplotlib.

### **Experience:**

Cognizant Aug 2021-Aug 2022

Data Analyst/Engineer - Project: Gilead US Commercial Analytics

Bengaluru, IND

GPA: 7.67/10.00

Chennai, India

GPA: 3.2/4

Chicago, IL

- Worked on the DAGs (Directed Acyclic Graph) using AWS Managed Apache Airflow and code Improvement using PySpark for extraction in AWS and worked with S3 for data storage.
- Engagement with end user to rectify issues related to data and backtracking in AWS Athena, also in EMR for better results.
- Collected data from different clients running through MySQL Commands, transformed data, loaded the data into the S3 buckets, and Triggering the DAGs
- Generated report after the load is completed, validated reports based on previous results, visualized and tracked the incoming issues and provided solution for the issues.

Cognizant Jan 2021- May 2021

Data Analyst Intern

Bengaluru, IND

- Collected data from the different teams, transformed the data by running MySQL queries, analyse the data using Python in Azure Databricks and visualize using Power BI.
- Gained knowledge on MySQL, Python, Azure Databricks, Microsoft SQL Server, Linux

# **Evolet Technologies**

Nov 2019 - Dec 2019

Java Developer - Intern

Bengaluru, IND

- Developed an Online Exam portal with a team of 4 for the school using HTML/CSS, ISP and Java.
- Involved in the software development life cycle including design, development, and testing.

### **Academic Projects:**

# Customer churn prediction on sparkify dataset

**Dec 2023** 

• This Project primarily focuses on using the Sparkify Dataset (small dataset - 128 Mb & complete dataset - 12 Gb) to predict customer churn (determine if the given customer will discontinue the subscription). Numerous user events from audio streaming services like Spotify and Pandora make up the collection. At first, we will analyze the mini dataset using Spark Dataframe, Spark SQL & Spark ML API locally using Pyspark and then deploy the spark cluster on AWS to run the model on the mini dataset. If time allows, we will apply the same procedure to the entire dataset. In addition, Tableau will be used to display the dataset's insights

#### **Sorting and Searching System**

Nov 2022

• Implemented all sorting and searching algorithms with the User Interface which sorts all kinds of data types and gives output in a sorted list including Total counts using technologies HTML/CSS, JSP & Java

## **COVID Symptoms Analyser**

**Iune 2020** 

• Developed a GUI based Application using Python library Tkinter to populate no. of symptoms for the individual to select in the application and based on the count (Severity) in the form of text the individual will understand either to take medication at home or to visit the hospital mandatorily

### **Certifications:**

- Azure Fundamentals: Microsoft Certified | Database Management essentials: Coursera
- Amazon Web Services: **Udemy** | Azure Databricks and Spark Core for Data Engineers: **Udemy**